♪In the face of turmoil♪
♪面对混乱♪
♪Your roots hold firmly♪
♪你的根牢牢地扎根♪
♪To this piece of land♪
♪为了这片土地♪
♪Chasing after the waves♪
♪追逐海浪♪
♪My leaves flutter across♪
♪我的树叶飘舞♪
♪The horizon♪
♪地平线♪
♪Gazing from afar♪
♪远远眺望♪
♪At the end of the world♪
♪世界的尽头♪
♪Is eternity♪
♪是永恒♪
♪When we meet and then part♪
♪当我们相遇又分离♪
♪When we rely on each other and then drift apart♪
♪当我们互相依赖 然后渐行渐远♪
♪I have never forgotten♪
♪我从未忘记♪
♪As the glinting of swords cut♪
♪剑刃闪烁♪
♪Through the mottled sky♪
♪穿过斑驳的天空♪
♪The falling dreams♪
♪坠落的梦想♪
♪Shatter in the wind♪
♪随风破碎♪
♪As the wind breaks through the waves♪
♪当风破浪时♪
♪It watches thousands of sails cross♪
♪它看着万千帆影交叉♪
♪The vast land and the boundless sea♪
♪广阔的土地和无边的海洋♪
♪Armor and red robes flying high♪
♪铠甲与红袍飞扬♪
♪In the face of bitterness, intense emotions, and joyful adventure♪
♪面对辛酸、 强烈的情感、愉快的冒险♪
♪I only wish you to be by my side♪
♪我只希望你能在我身边♪
♪Making the most of what life offers♪
♪充分利用生活所提供的一切♪
♪Like towering trees with interconnected roots, I'll accompany you to the ends♪
♪就像根相连的参天大树一样 ，我会陪你走到尽头♪
♪Watching fireflies land on our shoulders♪
♪看着萤火虫落在 我们的肩上♪
♪No regrets, no doubts in this world♪
♪这个世界没有遗憾，没有怀疑♪
=Wonderland of Love=
=爱的仙境=
=Episode 6=
=第6集=
(Han Residence)
（汉公馆）
Sorry for keeping you wait.
抱歉让您久等了。
Greetings, Lord Han.
韩老爷子您好。
I'm the envoy of Grand Governor.
我是大总督的使者。
How dare you stop me?
你怎么敢阻止我？
(Which)
（哪个）
Do you know that befriending Cui Yi privately
你知道 私下和崔毅交朋友吗
without informing Grand Governor is a crime?
不通知总督 是犯罪吗？
Please don't be mad.
请不要生气。
I was planning to invite you here
我本来打算邀请你来这里的
to discuss together.
一起讨论。
I didn't expect you to arrive so quickly.
我没想到你来得这么快。
You're from Cui Army?
你是崔军的？
Why did General Cui send you here?
崔将军为何派你来此？
Lord Han.
韩主。
Lieutenant He from Cui Army
崔军何中尉
is in your residence.
就在你的住处。
Please ask her out to meet me.
请约她出来见我。
Lieutenant He from Cui Army
崔军何中尉
is in my residence?
在我的住处吗？
There's no such thing.
没有这样的事。
Cui Army is right outside of Bingzhou.
崔军就在并州外。
If you insist on not releasing her,
如果你坚持不放她
don't blame us for entering the city to look for her.
别怪我们 进城来找她。
Lord Han.
韩主。
This is your fault.
这是你的错。
Zhenxi Rebel is right at our doorstep.
镇西叛军就在我们家门口。
Not only you're not working with Cui Army,
你不但 不跟崔军合作，
you're detaining
你拘留了
someone from Cui Army.
崔军的人。
You're oppressing our ally.
你在压迫我们的盟友。
I must report it to Grand Governor.
我必须向总督报告此事。
Listen to yourself.
听你自己说。
Nothing as such
没有这样的事
happened here.
发生在这里。
We haven't even seen
我们甚至没有见过
Lieutenant He you mentioned.
你提到的何中尉。
You can fool Cui Army,
你可以骗过崔军，
but you can't fool me.
但你骗不了我。
The guest room in the backyard is heavily guarded.
后院的客房戒备森严。
Even Golden Guards aren't allowed to get close.
就连金卫也 不许靠近。
People from Cui Army
崔军人
must have been imprisoned there.
一定是被囚禁在那里的。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
I'll take you to see Lieutenant He.
我带你去见何中尉。
Thank you.
谢谢。
No need.
不需要。
I'll ask
我会问
Young Master Cui and Lieutenant He out.
崔少爷 和何副官出来了。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Young Master.
少爷。
How are you?
你好吗？
Can you hold on?
你能坚持住吗？
Young Master.
少爷。
Why are you doing this?
你为什么做这个？
We only want to invite you to a banquet.
我们只是想邀请你参加一个宴会。
If you see our guest,
如果您看到我们的客人，
you'll surely be happy.
你一定会很高兴。
Lead the way.
带路。
Master, Young Master Cui is here.
少爷，崔公子来了。
You really do pamper the beauty, Young Master.
少爷您真是太宠美了。
It's a feast today.
今天真是一场盛宴。
I'm so fortunate.
我很幸运。
Young Master Cui,
崔少爷，
this is the envoy
这是特使
sent by Grand Governor.
大总督送来的。
I've long heard that Young Master Cui is charming.
我早就听说 崔公子很有魅力。
Now that I see you,
现在我见到你，
your reputation is well-deserved.
你的声誉是当之无愧的。
Greetings, Young Master.
你好，少爷。
Over ten thousand people from Cui Army
崔军万余人
are standing by outside Bingzhou,
守候在并州外，
waiting for your command.
等待你的命令。
Lord Han is detaining me and not letting me leave.
韩大人扣留我 不让我离开。
Here.
这里。
Tell the leader
告诉领导
that they can march in,
他们可以进军，
so everyone knows
所以大家都知道
how great Cui Army is.
崔军多么伟大。
You've misunderstood, Young Master Cui.
崔公子你误会了。
Outside of the city is crude.
城外的环境很简陋。
It's not
它不是
as comfortable as my mansion.
和我的豪宅一样舒适。
I just wanted to
我只是想
make you stay
让你留下来
for a few days more.
再过几天。
Don't worry, Young Master Cui.
崔公子放心吧。
If Grand Governor knows
如果大总督知道的话
that you're a guest in Bingzhou,
说你是并州的客人，
he'll surely have Lord Han
他一定会得到韩王爷的
send people to escort you into the capital.
派人护送 你进京城。
Xichang is a prosperous place.
西昌是一个繁华的地方。
You'll like it so much that you don't want to leave.
你会非常喜欢它 ，以至于不想离开。
Still hurt?
还受伤吗？
I'm inviting you to the capital on behalf of Grand Governor.
我代表总督邀请您来到首都。
You're so impolite.
你太没礼貌了
Are you looking down upon our Grand Governor?
你这是瞧不起 我们的大总督吗？
Calm down.
冷静下来。
Young Master Cui cares for the beauty.
崔少爷很爱美人。
It's the temperament of a young man.
这是年轻人的气质。
I'm the envoy of Grand Governor,
我是大总督的使者
equivalent to Grand Governor on an inspection tour.
相当于大督 巡视。
You're so arrogant.
你太嚣张了
You want to rebel?
你想造反吗？
Don't be angry.
别生气。
You have no idea.
你不知道。
Lady He
何女士
is the lover of Young Master Cui.
是崔少爷的情人。
In that case,
在这种情况下，
let's have Lady He perform a dance in the capital
让何夫人 到京城跳一支舞吧
to celebrate Grand Governor's birthday.
庆祝大总督的生日。
What do you mean by that?
你是什​​么意思？
Are you insulting Cui Army?
你这是在侮辱崔军吗？
Her foot is injured.
她的脚受伤了。
She can't dance.
她不会跳舞。
Why don't I perform a sword dance
我为什么不表演剑舞
for Grand Governor
为大总督
in her place?
代替她？
Great idea.
好想法。
I didn't expect
我没想到
to be so fortunate today.
今天能这么幸运。
Listen up.
听好了。
Prepare a sword.
准备一把剑。
No need.
不需要。
I shall borrow your sword.
我借你的剑。
You have no idea.
你不知道。
My sword
我的剑
is a gentleman's sword.
是君子之剑。
It has never been used.
它从未被使用过。
It's okay.
没关系。
I'm just using it for a performance,
我只是用它来表演
not for killing.
不是为了杀人。
You're humorous.
你很幽默。
Young Master is performing in my place.
少爷代替我表演。
I shall play the zither and sing
我会弹琴唱歌
as accompaniment.
作为伴奏。
The beauty does live up to
美丽确实辜负了
the kindness of Young Master Cui.
崔公子的恩情。
Young Master Cui, here you go.
崔少爷，来吧。
♪The Imperial Court needs talents♪
♪朝廷需要人才♪
♪Those who can kill enemies as fast as God♪
♪能像神一样快速杀死敌人的人♪
♪Sword dropped, dragon entwines the arm♪
♪剑落，龙缠绕手臂♪
♪Raise the flag, fire engulfs the body♪
♪升起旗帜，火焰吞噬身体♪
♪Corpses lying by the shore♪
♪岸边躺着尸体♪
♪Blood is spilled endlessly♪
♪鲜血不断流淌♪
♪The dance today♪
♪今天的舞会♪
♪Should show you that he's a warrior♪
♪应该让你知道他是一名战士♪
- Official.
- 官方的。
Charge!
收费！
Returning this to you.
把这个还给你。
Your sword dance
你的剑舞
is performed to one's heart content.
是尽情地表演。
How breathtaking.
多么令人叹为观止。
You've been very hospitable.
你一直非常热情好客。
I'm glad to help you
我很高兴为您提供帮助
solve your problem.
解决你的问题。
The envoy of Grand Governor
大督使
found out that you're here.
发现你在这里。
He insists to see you.
他坚持要见你。
Young Master.
少爷。
If this time
如果这个时候
you fall into the hands of Grand Governor,
你落入 总督手中，
I'm afraid it'll be hard for you to escape.
恐怕 你很难逃脱。
I only hope that your army outside of the city
我只希望 你的军队在城外
can scare the envoy.
可以吓唬使者。
I understand Lord Han's good intention.
我明白韩大人的良苦用心。
But your master
但你的主人
is very cunning.
非常狡猾。
He's unwilling to take action,
他不愿意采取行动，
and instead he passes this problem to us.
相反， 他把这个问题交给了我们。
You're kidding.
你在开玩笑。
After I kill Sun Jing's envoy,
我杀了孙敬的使者后
will you just let us go?
你能让我们走吗？
If I made a false promise on behalf of Lord Han,
如果我替韩王做出了虚假的承诺，
I would be deceiving you.
我会欺骗你。
But if you kill the envoy,
但如果你杀了使者
Lady He can go back.
何夫人可以回去了。
As for you,
至于你，
please stay for a few more days.
请多留几天。
After Cui Army
崔军之后
retreats for 60 miles,
撤退60英里，
you shall be allowed to return.
你将被允许返回。
Lord Han.
韩主。
Although the banquet is nice, there'll still be an end.
宴会虽然美好，但 终究还是要结束的。
Should you stick to your promise
你是否应该遵守你的承诺
and let her go?
然后放她走？
Of course.
当然。
Be sure
确定
to have a physician look at your wound closely.
让医生 仔细检查你的伤口。
Don't leave a chronic pain.
不要留下慢性疼痛。
Let's go. I'll see you off.
我们走吧。我来送你。
Here, be careful.
在这里，要小心。
For your luck.
为了你的好运。
Look at my awesome head.
看看我的头真棒。
If it's gone,
如果它消失了，
I wonder
我想知道
if anyone will cry for me.
如果有人会为我哭泣。
I won't.
我不会。
Charge!
收费！
Ying.
莹。
Young Master.
少爷。
- What's wrong with your foot? - It's fine.
- 你的脚怎么了？ - 没关系。
It's just a minor injury.
这只是一个轻伤。
No big deal.
没什么大不了。
Where's your hairpin?
你的发夹在哪里？
It was chaotic just now, I lost it accidentally.
刚才比较混乱， 一不小心就丢了。
I didn't look for it.
我没有找。
What a shame.
真丢脸。
It's your favourite thing
这是你最喜欢的东西
growing up.
成长。
But it's okay.
不过没关系。
I'll order you a new one.
我会给你订一件新的。
It's okay, Young Master. Forget it.
没关系，少爷。忘了它。
Are you tired?
你累了吗？
Let's go back and rest.
我们回去休息吧。
I ordered someone to cook a table
我吩咐人煮一桌菜
full of your favourite food.
充满了你最喜欢的食物。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Where is Lieutenant He's hairpin?
何中尉的发夹在哪里？
How would I know?
我怎么会知道？
When I arrived,
当我到达时，
Lieutenant's hairpin was already gone.
中尉的发夹已经不见了。
You're lying.
你在撒谎。
That hairpin is gifted to Lieutenant He
那簪子是送给何中尉的
by her mother.
由她母亲。
Even if she died,
就算她死了，
she wouldn't lose the hairpin.
她不会失去发夹。
Are you hiding something with Lieutenant He?
你是不是对何中尉有什么隐瞒？
No. It's really missing.
不，真的不见了。
She's very upset.
她很不高兴。
I stopped her
我阻止了她
from looking for it.
从寻找它。
It was too dangerous.
太危险了。
I don't trust you.
我不信任你。
(Palace of Xichang)
（西昌王府）
Look.
看。
How beautiful.
多么美丽。
Can I fly it higher?
我可以飞得更高吗？
You can.
你可以。
Madam, you're amazing.
女士，你太棒了。
Will it fall?
会掉吗？
Higher.
更高。
No.
不。
Higher. It won't fall.
更高。它不会掉落。
Look. It's so high and far.
看。它是如此之高和遥远。
It's so high, Madam.
太太太高了
Fly it.
飞吧。
It's raising.
它正在上涨。
Will it fall?
会掉吗？
No.
不。
- So beautiful. - So high.
- 如此美丽。 - 好高。
It's raising. So high.
它正在上涨。好高。
Madam, you're amazing.
女士，你太棒了。
Yes.
是的。
Whose kite is that?
那是谁的风筝？
Indeed.
的确。
What?
什么？
- It doesn't move. - Be careful, Madam.
- 它不动。 - 小心点，女士。
This...
这...
Let's go.
我们走吧。
It's you.
是你。
I didn't expect
我没想到
(First wife of Sun Jing, Madam of Wei) you to still have the mood.
（卫夫人孙敬原配） 你还有心情。
However,
然而，
your kite and my kite
你的风筝和我的风筝
are entangled.
被纠缠。
Cut it off.
截断。
Since you said so,
既然你都这么说了
then cut it off.
然后把它剪掉。
Yes.
是的。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
My kite
我的风筝
is gifted by Grand Governor.
是大总督赐予的。
It can't be lost.
它不能丢失。
Therefore,
所以，
we can only cut the line
我们只能断线
of your kite.
你的风筝。
Please forgive me, Madam of Wei.
请魏夫人恕罪。
You...
你...
Let's go!
我们走吧！
Consort Xiao is so rude.
萧妃真是太没礼貌了。
Does she think
她是否认为
she's still Crown Princess?
她还是太子妃？
She didn't even greet you.
她甚至没有跟你打招呼。
You're the first wife of Grand Governor.
你是大总督的第一任妻子 。
Consort Xiao is relying on her past relationship with Master.
萧妃就是仗着 她和老爷子过去的关系。
Right now Master
现在师父
is sympathizing her.
正在同情她。
Such a capricious
如此任性
and fickle woman.
和善变的女人。
I don't want to think like her.
我不想像她一样思考。
Your Highness.
殿下。
Madam of Wei is the first wife of Grand Governor.
韦夫人是 大都督的第一夫人。
You're in an awkward situation now.
你现在的处境很尴尬。
Why did you make her angry
你为什么惹她生气
because of such a small matter?
就因为这么一件小事？
If I want to send the pregnant Jiang
如果我要送 怀孕的江
out of the palace,
出了皇宫，
I have to do it through
我必须通过
Madam of Wei.
魏夫人。
Even a dull knife with a chipped edge,
即使是一把钝刀，边缘有缺口，
when it's used right,
当使用得当时，
can cut open
可以切开
the tightest cage.
最紧的笼子。
Lieutenant He.
何中尉。
Let me have a look at
让我看看
how your wound is.
你的伤口怎么样了。
No big deal.
没什么大不了。
I've applied medicine
我已经用药了
and bandaged it.
并用绷带包扎它。
Alright.
好吧。
But in the coming days,
但在接下来的日子里，
we have to keep applying medicine.
我们必须继续用药。
Or else,
要不然，
it may cause chronic pain.
它可能会导致慢性疼痛。
Okay, I'll listen to you.
好吧，我听你的。
By the way, Taozi,
顺便说一句，桃子，
this time
这次
He met Imperial Grandson, Li Ni.
他遇见了皇孙李妮。
He was the one who you wanted to
他就是你想要的那个人
shoot in the cottage.
在小屋里拍摄。
It's him?
是他？
Didn't you tell me that
你不是告诉过我吗
Li Ni
李妮
is the guise of Zhenxi Army
是镇西军的幌子
and surely is a useless idiot?
肯定是个没用的白痴？
I was wrong.
我错了。
This person is capable
这个人有能力
and very intelligent.
而且非常聪明。
Instead, we shouldn't
相反，我们不应该
take him lightly.
轻视他。
I didn't expect
我没想到
Li family
李家
to have such an outstanding offspring.
能有如此优秀的后代。
I haven't heard about him.
我没听说过他。
So what if he's great?
那就算他很厉害又怎样？
Is he as smart and capable as our lieutenant?
他像我们的中尉一样聪明能干吗 ？
Sweet-talker.
甜蜜的谈话者。
When I wasn't around,
当我不在身边的时候，
what did you eat?
你吃了什么？
They cooked me pork shoulder.
他们给我煮了猪肩肉。
I didn't expect
我没想到
Young Master Cui
崔少爷
to be a sentimental person.
做一个感性的人。
He saw Lady He left.
他看到何夫人离开了。
Tender melancholy.
温柔的忧郁。
Deplorable and sad.
可悲又悲伤。
A young hero
年轻的英雄
is always sentimental.
总是感性的。
Master.
掌握。
A letter from outside of the city.
一封来自城外的信。
Young Master Cui wrote it to you.
崔公子写给你的。
Young Master Cui?
崔少爷？
Isn't Young Master Cui in the residence?
崔公子不在府中吗？
Leave.
离开。
Yes, Master.
是的主人。
Young Master, Lieutenant He is here.
少爷，何中尉来了。
Ying.
莹。
I said I'll go to your tent,
我说过我会去你的帐篷
so you don't have to walk around with your injury.
这样你就不用 带着伤到处走动了。
Be careful.
当心。
It's okay.
没关系。
Just a minor injury.
只是受了点轻伤。
Since we're in the military camp,
既然我们在军营里
it's better for me to come to your tent to discuss.
我还是去你的帐篷里商量一下比较好。
Follow the rules.
按照规则。
Fortunately,
幸运的是，
you're back safely.
你安全回来了。
By the way,
顺便一提，
what do you think about the current situation?
您对目前的情况有何看法？
Although Zhenxi Army
虽然镇西军
took down Wangzhou,
拿下望州，
without Bingzhou and Jianzhou,
没有并州、建州，
they can't
他们不能
move a step closer to Tong Pass.
距离潼关又近了一步。
As for Xichang,
至于西昌，
it's even more out of reach.
更是遥不可及。
You're right.
你说得对。
I think so too.
我也这么认为。
I think since we have the military power,
我想既然我们有军事实力
why don't we attack Bingzhou?
为何不攻打并州？
When we have Bingzhou and Jianzhou,
到了并州、建州，
it doesn't matter if it's Sun Jing or Li Ni,
不管是孙静还是李妮，
they'll have to act according to Cui Army.
他们就得 按照崔军的吩咐行事。
Young Master.
少爷。
This time
这次
I actually met Li Ni.
我居然遇见了李妮。
This person
这个人
can't be taken lightly.
不能掉以轻心。
He's a rare opponent.
他是一个罕见的对手。
We're the one who should be on guard instead.
我们才是最应该警惕的人。
What kind of person is he?
他是一个什么样的人？
That he made you say such things.
他让你说出这样的话。
This person
这个人
is great,
是很棒的，
but it's not that
但不是那样的
we have no way
我们没有办法
to take down Bingzhou.
攻下并州。
We need a perfect strategy.
我们需要一个完美的策略。
What good way do you have
你有什么好办法
to take down Bingzhou?
拿下并州？
Isn't General Pei Yuan
不是裴渊将军吗
in Wangzhou?
在望州？
Why don't we
我们为什么不
reminisce with him first?
先跟他回忆一下？
But we rarely have contact with Zhenxi Army.
但我们与镇西军却很少接触。
On the contrary, we argued because of military rations.
相反，我们 因为军粮而争吵。
I'm afraid
我耽心
they won't form allies with us so easily.
他们不会那么容易与我们结盟 。
Even if we do,
即使我们这样做，
I'm afraid they'll have different intentions.
恐怕 他们会有不同的意图。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
I have a way
我有办法
for them to agree to form allies.
让他们同意结成盟友。
I also have a way
我也有办法
to avoid different intentions.
以避免不同的意图。
(The one in your residence is not me.) I'm so angry.
（你住处的不是我。） 我很生气。
Cui family has crossed the line.
崔家已经越界了。
What happened, Master?
发生什么事了，师父？
Go!
去！
Go get the fake Young Master Cui
去找那个假崔少爷
imprisoned right now.
现在被监禁了。
Yes, Master.
是的主人。
No. Kill him immediately!
不行，立刻杀了他！
Take him.
带他。
What else do you want to say?
你还想说什么？
Lord Han.
韩主。
I'll be honest.
我会说实话。
I'm Young Master Cui's study partner.
我是崔少爷的学习伙伴。
I got his order to come here
我接到他的命令来这​​里
and discuss something important with you.
并与您讨论一些重要的事情。
Unexpectedly,
不料，
you mistook me as Young Master Cui.
你误会我是崔少爷了。
Under the instruction of Lieutenant He,
在何中尉的指挥下，
I took advantage of the mistake.
我利用了这个错误。
But I didn't intent
但我不是故意的
to lie to you.
对你撒谎。
I went through fire and water for Cui family.
我 为崔家赴汤蹈火。
But I didn't expect them
但我没想到他们
to betray me today,
今天背叛我，
let alone being abandoned.
更不用说被抛弃了。
Since you know that you're abandoned,
既然你知道自己被抛弃了，
what other use do you have?
你还有什么用处？
Lord Han.
韩主。
Since Cui family is unkind to me,
既然崔家对我不客气，
I'll return this injustice.
我一定会回报这种不公正的待遇。
I have a plan
我有个计划
that can solve your urgency.
可以解决你的燃眉之急。
I know that Cui Army has robbed
我知道崔军抢劫了
the ration of Zhenxi Army.
镇西军的口粮。
Zhenxi Army is desperate of ration.
镇西军口粮匮乏。
They hate Cui Army's guts.
他们恨崔军的胆量。
Why don't you send someone to Wangzhou
不如派人去望州吧
to discuss an ally with Li Ni
与李妮商议结盟事宜
to destroy Cui Army?
灭崔军？
You'll be rescued
你会获救的
and Zhenxi Army will get their ration.
镇西军将得到口粮。
Master.
掌握。
He has got his points.
他有他的观点。
Our spy
我们的间谍
has also reported
还报道过
about the robbed ration.
关于被抢的口粮。
I'm just someone
我只是一个人
abandoned by Cui family.
被崔家抛弃。
I have nothing.
我什么都没有。
Only you can give me a chance to live.
只有你能给我活下去的机会。
Lord Han.
韩主。
Why don't you have someone get the opinion of Zhenxi Army?
为什么不让人 征求一下镇西军的意见呢？
As for me,
至于我，
you don't have to
你不必
kill me instantly.
立刻杀了我。
If Zhenxi Army doesn't agree,
如果镇西军不同意
it's not too late to kill me then.
到时候杀了我还不算太晚。
If this plan works,
如果这个计划成功的话
I'm willing to follow you
我愿意追随你
and be at your service.
竭诚为您服务。
Take him down
把他拿下来
and imprison him.
并监禁他。
Come along.
一起来。
The prisoner is here.
囚犯就在这里。
Keep him in this cell.
把他关在这个牢房里。
(Guo Residence)
(Guo Residence)
General Pei Yuan.
General Pei Yuan.
Mister Shiqi is found.
世奇先生被发现了。
Really?
真的吗？
Where is he?
他在哪里？
Cui Army reported
崔军报道
that Mister Shiqi
that Mister Shiqi
is in Han Li's residence in Bingzhou.
并州韩立府邸内。
What is he doing there?
他在那里做什么？
I asked, but she didn't want to answer.
我问，但她不想回答。
She wants to see you and report the details in person.
她想见你 并亲自报告详细情况。
See me in person?
亲自见我吗？
Who is that?
那是谁？
She's a very fierce young lady.
她是一位非常凶猛的年轻女士。
She knows how to use poison
她知道如何使用毒药
and fight.
并战斗。
She's fierce and formidable.
她凶猛而令人畏惧。
Greetings, General Pei Yuan.
裴远将军，您好。
Raise.
增加。
Lieutenant He
何中尉
sent me here to see you.
派我来见你。
The whereabouts of Li Ni
李妮的去向
is a present
是一份礼物
from Cui Army to you.
从崔军到你。
With this
有了这个
we would like to show the sincerity of Cui Army.
我们要展现 崔军的诚意。
Speaking of which,
说到这，
Li Ni and Lieutenant He
Li Ni and Lieutenant He
are quite fated.
都是很有缘分的。
Awhile ago,
不久以前，
Lieutenant He saved Li Ni a couple of times.
何中尉救过李妮 几次。
This time
这次
she also doesn't want to see him dead.
她也不想看到他死。
Therefore, Cui Army
因此，崔军
is willing to form an ally with you
愿意与你结成盟友
to rescue Li Ni.
去营救李妮。
Really?
真的吗？
Lieutenant He said
何中尉说
if I say this,
如果我这么说
you'll most likely not believe me.
你很可能不相信我。
However,
然而，
you can send someone
你可以派人
to find it out in Bingzhou.
到并州一探究竟。
Then you'll know if we're speaking the truth.
然后你就会知道 我们说的是不是实话。
General Pei Yuan. Gen...
General Pei Yuan. Gen...
Lieutenant He also said
何中尉还说
if I arrive at the right time,
如果我在正确的时间到达
at this point
在此刻
Han Li from Bingzhou
Han Li from Bingzhou
will also send someone
也会派人
to discuss an important issue with you.
与您讨论一个重要问题。
I wonder
我想知道
if Han Li sent someone over.
如果韩立派人过来的话。
This young lady
这位年轻女士
is really accurate.
真的很准确。
Han Li really sent someone over?
韩立真的派人过来了？
Yes.
是的。
See.
看。
Our lieutenant has taken everything into account.
我们的中尉已经 考虑到了一切。
Mister Shiqi.
Mister Shiqi.
We brought many people to save you.
我们带了很多人来救你。
How many?
多少？
Six.
六。
Go back.
回去。
What's wrong?
怎么了？
I don't know what happened,
我不知道发生了什么
my stomach isn't feeling well.
我的胃不舒服。
My stomach grumbles.
我的肚子咕咕叫。
Hurry back.
快回来。
Okay.
好的。
Lieutenant He.
何中尉。
Do you really think
你真的认为
we can work with Zhenxi Army?
我们可以和镇西军合作吗？
The marshal of Zhenxi Army, Li Ni,
The marshal of Zhenxi Army, Li Ni,
is the smartest
是最聪明的
and trickiest person I've seen.
也是我见过的最狡猾的人。
Even if you restrain him
就算你限制他
with metal chains,
搭配金属链条，
(put him in a box,)
（把他放进盒子里，）
(tie it to a rock and then sink him into the river.)
（将其绑在岩石上 ，然后将其沉入河中。）
(In a blink of an eye,)
（一眨眼的功夫，）
(he'll float to the surface)
（他会浮到水面）
and with a smile
并带着微笑
he'll trick you back.
他会把你骗回来。
Of course we can
当然，我们可以
work with such a smart person.
和这样一个聪明的人一起工作。
Why are you so sure
你为什么这么确定
that Li Ni
那个李妮
can persuade Han Li
can persuade Han Li
to send someone to see Pei Yuan?
派人去见裴渊？
Li Ni
李妮
is an expert
是一位专家
in escaping death.
在逃脱死亡的过程中。
I'm very sure
我非常确定
that we'll be able to persuade Han Li
我们就能说服韩立
and set up a double-trick trap for him.
并为他设下双招陷阱。
In that case,
在这种情况下，
why don't we
我们为什么不
take advantage of his trap
利用他的陷阱
to make it our trap?
让它成为我们的陷阱？
You're quite capable.
你很有能力。
Pei Yuan actually agreed
裴媛居然同意了
to work with us
与我们合作
to attack Cui Army from both sides.
从两面攻击崔军。
However,
然而，
he has one term.
他只有一个任期。
Other than keeping the food supplies of Cui Army,
除了保留崔军的粮食补给之外，
he wants to take the passage via Jianzhou to the south.
他想走 经由建州的通道向南走。
To be honest,
说实话，
if Pei Yuan didn't have any terms,
如果裴媛没有任何条件的话
you shouldn't even believe him.
你甚至不应该相信他。
Since he brought up a condition,
既然他提出了一个条件，
I think
我认为
this is most likely going to work.
这很可能会起作用。
Tell me more.
告诉我更多。
You can pretend to agree to his passage.
你可以假装同意他的通过。
Jianzhou has a dangerous terrain.
建州地势险要。
Your garrison can make use of the terrain to attack with lesser manpower.
你的驻军可以利用地形 以较少的人力进行攻击。
When Zhenxi Army is in Xialuo Valley,
镇西军在下洛谷时，
by clutching them from front and back,
从前面和后面抓住它们，
we can severely damage Zhenxi Army.
我们可以重创镇西军。
First destroy Cui Army,
先灭崔军，
then severely damage Zhenxi Army.
继而重创镇西军。
Then,
然后，
even Grand Governor Sun
就连孙大督
in the capital
在首都
can no longer oppress you.
不能再压迫你了。
You've read books on art of war?
你读过兵法书籍吗？
I'm the study partner of Young Master Cui.
我是崔少爷的学习伙伴。
The four arts of Chinese scholar,
中国学者的四艺，
military leadership and strategy,
军事领导和战略，
I've studied them all.
我已经全部研究过了。
Very well.
很好。
You're a talented person.
你是一个有才华的人。
I'm flattered, Lord Han.
韩大人，我受宠若惊。
I'm born in a chaotic world.
我出生在一个混乱的世界。
I just want to survive.
我只想活下去。
I'm willing to
我愿意
be at your service.
竭诚为您服务。
I still have to
我还得
test your capabilities.
测试你的能力。
I'm sorry that you still have to stay in the prison.
很遗憾 你还得待在监狱里。
In the future,
将来，
if I really am able to damage Zhenxi Army,
如果我真的能够 击伤镇西军
I'll release you
我会释放你
and make you my adviser.
并让你成为我的顾问。
Thank you, Lord Han.
谢谢韩大人。
Why are you behaving oddly
你为什么行为怪异
every time you mention Li Ni?
每次提到李妮？
How odd?
有多奇怪？
You seem to hate him
看来你很讨厌他
very much.
非常。
Don't I?
我不是吗？
In that case,
在这种情况下，
why must we save him?
为什么我们必须救他？
He's such an interesting person.
他是一个非常有趣的人。
It'll be a shame if he dies.
如果他死了那就太可惜了。
That's true.
这是真的。
I've never heard you
我从来没有听说过你
describe someone this way.
这样描述某人。
I've also not heard
我也没有听说过
you call anyone
你打电话给任何人
as your opponent.
作为你的对手。
Who's your opponent?
你的对手是谁？
Young Master.
少爷。
Nothing.
没有什么。
I'm just chatting with Taozi.
我只是在跟桃子聊天而已。
Ying.
莹。
I have something for you.
我有东西给你。
The hairpin your mother left you...
你妈妈留给你的发夹...
I know
我知道
you must be sad to have lost it.
失去它你一定很难过。
Look.
看。
Doesn't it look very similar to your old one?
是不是看起来 和你以前的很相似呢？
It does.
确实如此。
I made it myself.
我自己做的。
Let me put it on.
让我把它戴上。
Young Master.
少爷。
The old hairpin
老发夹
has a different meaning to me.
对我来说有不同的意义。
Even if they look alike,
即使他们长得很像
I don't want to replace the old one
我不想换旧的
with another hairpin.
用另一个发夹。
Thank you for your thought.
谢谢你的想法。
I'll keep
我会保留
this hairpin safely.
这个发夹安全。
Okay.
好的。
Ying.
莹。
Don't you think
你不觉得
I have no idea about your plan.
我不知道你的计划。
When I'm out,
当我出去的时候，
I'll deal with you about this.
我会和你处理这件事。
Lord Han told me to visit you.
韩大人吩咐我去拜访你。
He's afraid that you'll be upset.
他怕你不高兴。
Lord Han is so kind.
韩老爷子真是太仁慈了。
Thank you, Mister Lv.
谢谢你，吕先生。
I'm not upset.
我没有不高兴。
I'm abandoned by Cui Army.
我被崔军抛弃了。
Thanks to Lord Han
感谢韩大人
for sparing my life
为了饶我一命
and listening to my plans.
并听取我的计划。
I'm more than grateful,
我无比感激，
why would I be upset?
我为什么会不高兴？
Okay.
好的。
I knew you're an open-minded person.
我知道你是一个思想开放的人。
I brought some good liquor along.
我带了一些好酒。
Let's have a drink.
我们喝一杯吧。
This liquor smells good.
这酒的味道很好闻。
This is a fine liquor of Lord Han,
这是汉王的美酒，
of course it smells good.
当然闻起来很香。
You're right.
你说得对。
The enemy is attacking.
敌人正在进攻。
- Something bad happened. - The enemy is attacking.
- 发生了不好的事情。 - 敌人正在进攻。
(Zhenxi)
(Zhenxi)
(Li)
（李）
(Which)
（哪个）
Send my order,
发送我的订单，
attack!
攻击！
In this war we're charging in on horseback.
在这场战争中，我们骑马冲锋。
Even more fun than attacking Wangzhou last time.
比上次攻打望州还要好玩。
Youren, have you ridden a horse before?
幽仁，你骑过马吗？
When I learned to ride a horse,
当我学会骑马的时候
you were just a foolish child.
你只是一个愚蠢的孩子。
Take down Bingzhou! Charge!
拿下并州！收费！
Charge!
收费！
(Zhenxi)
(Zhenxi)
I'll send someone to find out.
我会派人去查清楚。
Hurry.
匆忙。
Yes.
是的。
Here.
这里。
Let's drink this up.
让我们把这个喝完吧。
Sorry for the past.
对过去感到抱歉。
In the future,
将来，
please share your guidance.
请分享您的指导。
Here.
这里。
Good liquor.
好酒。
Young man.
年轻人。
We've known each other for awhile.
我们认识有一段时间了。
It feels like we've known each other all along.
感觉就像我们 一直以来就认识一样。
But I don't know
但我不知道
what your name is
你叫什么名字
and where you're from.
以及你来自哪里。
How did you become
你是怎么变成的
Young Master Cui's study partner?
崔少的学习伙伴？
Tell me about it.
告诉我怎么回事儿。
Well,
出色地，
it's a long story.
说来话长。
I can only tell you in details in awhile.
我只能 稍后再详细告诉你。
Why
为什么
in awhile?
等一下？
What's that noise?
那是什么声音？
I can tell you now.
我现在可以告诉你。
My name is Li Ni.
我叫李妮。
I'm the seventeenth one.
我是第十七个。
The grandson of the late emperor.
已故皇帝的孙子。
The son of Lord Liang.
梁公之子。
The marshal of Zhenxi Army.
镇西军元帅。
Bringing peace to the world
给世界带来和平
and killing all the rebels.
并杀死所有叛乱分子。
Remember that.
请记住这一点。
♪If I forget the fleeting of time♪
♪如果我忘记了转瞬即逝的时光♪
♪Waiting for memories♪
♪等待回忆♪
♪To shatter and sink♪
♪破碎并沉没♪
♪The emotional scars in your heart♪
♪你心中的情感伤痕♪
♪Are the entanglement♪
♪是纠缠♪
♪I find hard to let go of♪
♪我发现很难放手♪
♪If longing is not forgotten♪
♪如果没有忘记渴望的话♪
♪I long to return to the very first moment♪
♪我渴望回到 最初的那一刻♪
♪The affection we had in our fateful situation♪
♪我们在命运的处境中所拥有的感情♪
♪How I wish to keep it for you♪
♪我多么想为你保留它♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪The promises we made♪
♪我们的约定♪
♪Even if this love hurts me♪
♪即使这份爱让我受伤♪
♪I'll continue living for you♪
♪我会继续为你而活♪
♪Holding onto the memories♪
♪紧紧抓住回忆♪
♪Waiting is my persistence♪
♪等待是我的坚持♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪The promise I made to you♪
♪我对你的承诺♪
♪Despite going against fate♪
♪尽管违背命运♪
♪I have no regrets loving you♪
♪我不后悔爱你♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪我愿意为你牺牲♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪等待你的答复♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪The promise I made to you♪
♪我对你的承诺♪
♪Despite going against fate♪
♪尽管违背命运♪
♪I have no regrets loving you♪
♪我不后悔爱你♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪我愿意为你牺牲♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪等待你的答复♪